Farhan : So, we can conclude its better to pick library that support the OS of most user, right?.
Yes, Sure. Because there are several libraries that depend on each other.
Is there anyone here who has ever developed an Android application? With Native?.
Not yet.
Farhan : We actually have a lecture about mobile programming at fifth semester i think.
Ohh Ok Ok. Just self-taught, there are many lessons hehe.
Just Self-taught. Many lessons.
Because if we waiting for Campus, that's long haha.
Farhan : yes, you right, it will be long.
Yes like that. Just explore it and wait for the Campus.
So, in Android, We have many external libraries. So we dont use the default from Google, because it's not enough.
So we use an External Library.
Sometimes the external library is depend by other external library. So like that and it's very troublesome if the project is big.
If the project is big, we don't know how many libraries that depends each others.
Like so. Who knows if i upload one library and then
i forget this library is depends with other three library, like that.
Because only update one library (the minor), automatically the relation with other is not supported.
This is often to happen. So, the update of the library is get into major improvement.
What is major improvement? Althought the version is up a little bit, like so.
Because, it could be depends by other library. it must be checked again when the version is up, we must testing again, like that.
That's what the most happen in Mobile. Android especially.
Farhan: we are still in the third semester, and we still learn from the theory.
Yes true, yes true.
Yes true, like so.
Farhan: we dont have much experience like software testing, software development just like you said just now, i dont even know the process of making application entirely. cause you just what i said just know, we are still in the third semester
Ohh ok ok, yes yes. That's fine.
You will internship, right? Later during the internship, you can also studying.
Farhan: yes, maybe in fifth semester or seventh? i forgot.
Haha, that's still took a long time, Bro. Haha.
If possible, you can internship at start up.
Farhan: In which kind of startup?.
New Boss, because you guys will have many lessons, usually.
That's my experince at Start Up.
Isn't Start Up must have a high hard work?
Ohh, you means the works is heavier?
Yes, like must got carried at the beginning.
That's true. In my opinion, if you are doing an intership at the settle company, you're task is limit at that point.
Sometimes there is no task, usually a new student just like that, like so.
We are not trusted to handle a big task, that usually happen to a new interner.
If at the Start Up, because the limit of human source and cost efficiency, etc, finally they use whatever is there, like that.
So you will be guided by Senior Programmer in there to try to build like this, etc. So at the end, usually will be given more trust.
So you will be handle a live field-project, so you're role will learn many things.
Just for sure that will be more hard compare to Settle. But like Traveloka, Gojek, etc it's still Okay.
I mean, they're not yet like... Do you guys have heard about Agile?
Farhan: yes i have heard of it.
Agile ohh Agile.. Yes yes.
Farhan: oh Agile framework, like scrum right?
Yes true, Scrum. That's it.
A Company like that is usually adopted an Agile so they work will be efficient and keep maintenance.
Sometimes on a big Company if the task is done, they will do nothing like a week.
That's the point, so i recommend to go to place like Start Up and implement that.
Sometimes, usually that's pity. The thing is when we intern, we need to absorb many knowledge first, like that.
That's pity if we intern at place like we don't get much knowledge at there. So, as well as an intern in a good place, like so to get more knowledge.
Farhan: does startup usually always accept an intern?
Yes. Honestly if a New Start Up, they will looking for intern, Why? Because while there is money.
Farhan: Because intern doesnt get paid right? i think its gonna be somekind a symbiotic mutualism, where the intern got the experience and the start up got a indirectly free employee right?
Yes. That's what i'm doing that time haha.
So, first is efficiency cost, second is we like... in Programmer, there is a Senior, Middle, Junior.
If a Senior Programmer, they have they own principle, own framework, like that. Usually it has been difficult to be channeled.
So usually, if it's me, if i'm like hiring or finding a developer is looking a fresh graduate which is have a new experience like 1 or 2 years.
Why? Because i can try to synchronize how the development process, how to program, etc.
So, it's according to what is done in the office.
Sometimes, if it's like that is still accepted, like that.
That's it.
Farhan: Closing the discussion , and thanking to the developer for the time
Yeah, You're welcome.
Yes, You're Welcome. Waallaikumsalam
Thank youu, Broo.