-Farhan : (well, if you click "go to the play store" it will go directly to your apps)
-yes, you right, okay this is the website version
-so, its not me who created this website, i think he made it using wordpress, if im not wrong
-so he can make it fast, for android, because he want to make it custom, so i make the android one separately
-okay, i think thats all from me
-there so many points that i missed for the UI and UX
-and for the UI i think this still a mockup and not ready to implement to the app
- So there must be something more like the bridge., usually the one who give something like this in software house are ......
........product manager. from the client, the client talk to the project manager. Usually, product manager make a mock-up first like the previous picture.
-then the product manager give it to the  UI UX designer
-and the UX designer are the one who will port from what kind of platform did the client told us
-so this mock-up is not a reference for the design but a connection for the business process.
-later, the design can change 180 degrees.
-but the menu still in there. That's what usually happens in software houses.
-product manager design didnt follow any design guidelines. they just following what client requested
-so they really following the client request. then,after enter the UI UX......
.......and this UI UX job is a little bit difficult because they have to know what is this application used to
-they have to know the goals, the important feature,etc. Well... it's quite heavy at the beginning. So they designed it really accoridng to the user journey
-so the heavy part about UI UX are at the research part, we really have to imagine what the user wants
-oh, yes
-okay
-Farhan : (what kind of programming languange did you use to make this liz transport app?)
-programming?
-Farhan: (yes, the one you used to code the backend)
-oh okay
-Farhan: (is it kotlin?Flutter? etc)
-i made this using java native, for the programming languange is java, but there is a couple library that i use to make this app
-for now i think kotlin is better, have you ever know kotlin?
-yes we know it
-yes, we usually use kotlin if its native. but before kotlin was created, i used java because i mastered java and i think its java are more fast than kotlin for development
-i think kotlin now are more fast for development and more eficient than java
-have you ever heard getter and setter?
-yes we know
-Farhan: ( we actually learn that in this semester)
-oh, yes
-the getter setter class in java are about 40 line, but in kotlin are just 2 line. that was a big difference i think
-Farhan : ( its same like python and C++ right?)
-yeah, i think about like that, but kotlin is far more efficient i think
-only it depends on you, for java itself, if you describe it
-java, if you compile it, it wiil go into the assembly,then it will enter machine language. So only 2 layers.
-but for kotlin, it will enters java, then assembly and then enter the machine languange. so there are a lot of layers for kotlin
- so to make a heavy application, i still recommend you to use java because its lighter to compile than kotlin
-but for a simple apps like liz transport, i think kotlin and java are just the same. so like that.
-i think mobile programming right now are goin to hybrid, have you ever heard react?
-oh yes
-but now the popular one is flutter i think, back then react is really popular
-because react is an open source, react is a write once to build all platform
-then , flutter show up, flutter is a bit differet from react, then the react developers are move to the flutter
-why reacts is different is, one react code still cant directly converted to android and ios
-because react still using android sdk and ios compiler
-when we going to porting to ios and anrdoid, , the UI have to changed, about 70% of the code still usable but the 30% has to be modified again, and thats react
-and flutter, is 100% can be directly run to IOS and android without porting it again
-so thats the reason why developer move from react to flutter. and for the performance, in some case flutter go more fast than native
-Farhan : (so indirectly it is better)
-yes its better, but the difference flutter is really depends on google
-Farhan: (okay, i wanna ask something, how can you add your application to the playstore?like uploading the apps to playstore or something)
-oh, its like to create an email, but its enter the developer website
-the developer google.com, but we must pay 25$ using credit cards
-so you must provide a credit card. we can use a credit card like jenius. have you ever heard jenius?
-yeah the e-card one, it can be deposit a balance about four hundred then it can be added to playstore
-well, its easy to add your apps to playstore, but you have to prepare an asset , description application and... can i share my screen?
-so you guys can see it directly
-yes, to make we can see directly
-Farhan :( i think we have to come directly to the google office)
The Developer Change the Account
-sorry i change the account
-okay, can you guys see it?
-so its something like this, to register it you can go to the google play store and fill the form like credit card etc
-then after we enter it, you got some interface like this
-in here, there is a list of an application. and this one is not fit to the criteria
-then after create, we enter the name, then we will try liz here
-here, we must prepare the apk, there is 2 kind of apk , the unsign one, the unsign is an apk that not have the key to public
-now the second sign is. The one going to the play store is the sign one. Now there is what is released, this is in the form of an APK.
-then store presence are for put apps information, the title, description even the icon, just follow it
-and here is to put application screenshoot, there is no minimal quantity for screenshot, but the max is 8 . and the images usually are potrait
-then graph, then final one is to input content rating. for example this liz transport can be use by anyone, all ages.
-if there is any question about this apps, you can answer it here
-then click save, you just have to wait about 3 days for google to add it to the playstore
-but , if there is a pandemic condition like now, you have to wait about a week for adding or updating your apps. its actually a bit easy to add your apps to playstore
-can i ask a question? i dont really know about mobile programming
-but as you can see, every android update there is a new API right?
-as a mobile developer, how important if there is a broken API, while we must support handphone with an old OS?
-yup, it have to be like this, it depends on the application, if we see the ratio all of android user, android lower than 5 are have a few user than 5 above
-like that, we must see the condition. Sometimes , library just support some OS like lolipop
-if user have android version lower than lolipop , the apps will crash or broken. to prevent that, choose a library that google provide
-if we try to make cycle view for example, cycle view can be made from another developer and can be made from google too
-try to use the one that google make
-for this liz transport, i think i use the library that google provide. so before you want to use a library from another developer , try to find a library that google provide
-because with the library that google provide, even user with old OS still can access the application
-because if you use the third party library, it really depends on the developer that created it
-so the first thing, when maintaining library.....
.....you must pick a trusted library author, there are some developer that always update their library
-beside google, you can find developer like this,
- but there is some developer that didint update the library, and the second one you must see the change log
-so you can see the change, it is okay if there is a minor change, the one that makes us troule just like yesterday, back then , android use Fo 4
- it is the name of the android bundling, android have a bundling. until the android 8/9 is still using the same bundling
-then suddenly android X change the bundling, because of that the library must be changes
-when android 10 appeared,not all the library can be use, there so many changes in the library. this is a major change
-we must find a library that always update,and we must check the change log , does the library support android X or maybe lower,or maybe in the future there is android 20
-yes , check it right there, maybe like that. oh yeah the final one is while in development, usually we test it about a week
-so if we enter the testing week before release, we must fix all the library version in the entire project
-tomorrow , we will have a data, okay keep it in there until the beta testing done until published
-we must do it in the next version. its to prevent us to make a sudden upgrade
-and , evidently it affecting to the other library. because we dont check the change of the library. its usuallly happen like that
-so its better to skip 1 or 2 version, and waiting it to be stable. Like that