-Yep, thats it
-okay, from me, for the first time, thanks
-Initially, I made this liz transportation application, not until a week, only about 3-4 days.
-we dont focus at design on this application
-so there is a couple point that i think it would be good l like maps, the reservation and history sections can be combined......
.....or the menu can be made even more concise.
-Continue to log out, profile, etc. which I also missed.
-okay , maybe......
-there is 2 section , UI and UX right, for the UX i think that has been a lot of input from you guys
-from the UI, Are you guys designing this with XD?
-Yes, we design this with XD
-Farhan: (is there any input for our team about this improvement ?)
-okay, maybe i can try to share it, can you see it?
-from my opinion, more to the design, but for the UX, there is a lot of good improvement,
-it should be like that, so the point that presented by akbar, i think its already good enough
-Maybe just at the UI, because if I look at the mockup that Akbar shared with, its already a mockup instead of anyother else
-there is a last version that it's prepared to implement in the mock-up, so it continues to fit in the application.
-from the mocup , if we want to implement to the android application
-Android has an design bridge called material design, its like design guideline from google
-convert it first according to the design material, then the output will come out like what can only be implemented into the application.
-so, as what i saw from the UI just now
-just add guidelines from material design and then...
-the for the car section, from my opinion , the grid utilization just now
-this is linear right? why i use linear is ......
....e-commerce has any kind of image and has a low image resolution........
....so it will show more for the content while in this rental application, the quantity is limited, not many cars
-then the second one is that the resolution I got is high-resolution, so it's good to be displayed in full size.
-so what if we make it grid, it will be seems like a little bit out of content. Like if we make it grid , its just shown us three rows
-so thats the why i pick the linear one, then after that
-just now the slider one is good. here why i make it an animated background because i just got one photo of this car
- so it cant be like a slider image, and the rest of it , i think its already good enough
-maybe the last one is just the UI, at the design part
-use the UI design guidelines that requested by the platform. for IOS , it has flat design
-there is a flat guiedlines, and for android, there is a material design
- So they didn't just teach "How to design?" but they teach the UX too. Because there are also icons like what kind of good to use for online contrast like this.
-then background utilization,space, margin and then shadow, this one has a kind of drop shadow at the card
-The intensity also has rules. The point is they want the applications on Android to be in the same circle as the OS.
-so the design not changed drastically, like that
-Farhan : (So its basicaly similiar each other)
-yes you right, So the look and feel are the same. Between the OS and the application therein is on the same base, namely material design.
-so that all from me maybe, In XD, I have tried it in the "new project" column. It's like downloading a plug-in or downloading a design
It's like a kit for material and a kit for flat. It contains icons, components on Android. You can use from there too.
-it was there the last time i saw it, like that
-Farhan:(is a kit for material really there?)
-wait i will try to open it, from the older version , its supposed to be somewher around here
- i think we must download it
-Farhan: (Actually we use a couple of plugins but not material plugin, i forgot what its called, Akbar do you remember what it is called?)
-what ? which one?
-Farhan:(the icon plugin one)
-oh yeah the icon one
-Oh yes, this is on the material website. There is a plug-in. There is a design kit for adobe XD
-they provided us with a font ,continue button. So if you want to copy it, make a button, so it's not difficult to make a button again.
-just copy and change the colour according to the application, and the grid is already exist too
-so it will be more better to implement it
-Farhan: (i was wondering, are you learn all the material design from this website called material.io?)
-Oh, I happen to think the material had training at the beginning. That's a drastic change from the old material to the new one.
-from the hollow one
-oh yeah hollow
-well, Google used to do training for developers who want to migrate to materials, and i join the training
-its hard to following the traininig because they really explained the details like a philosophy of material
-is it kind of bootcamor something?
-yes , its kind of bootcamp for android developer in bandung
-so if you guys read the website, its all complete , there is all explanation why did they make like that, but its kinda hard i think to understand
-but from me, i think its enough from just XD material design kit
-and its just remains to be learned, there is already a guidelines inside of it so you can just follow it
-and you must following the rules. As far as i know, right now playstore doesn't accept an application that whose rules are far from the material
-sometimes it can be rejected
-Farhan: (so its like a standarization for a design and the applicaton right?)
-yes, its like a standarization, It's okay for you to make your own design, but it is still acceptable based on the material.
-yes, I  made a game, right? i think make a game is a little hard to follow the material guidelines
-then it was rejected, but they given the solution to make it acceptable
-I also downloaded the kits earlier in the material, are you find the icon by yourself?
-yes from plugin
-Farhan:(we got the icon from the plugin)
-Farhan : (we got the plugin from the bottom left corner)
-yes the bottom one
-oh, from this one, okey then
-Farhan: (does material design provide us all the icon that you use to make the application?)
-yes, for the standard action like......okay where is it
-okay for example the logout button. the material provided the logout button. so for the standar action in apps, you can pick it from the material kit
-and for the bottom button, I don't use materials. I downloaded it too.
-actually we don't always have to use material design, because....
...... its depends on client, usually material looks stiffer. Because this is where the basics coming from.
-so if you want make your own design, as you follow the material guidelines, its stiaceeptable. Here the bottom one i didn't use the material icon
-because if i use material people gonna.....yeah
-people maybe gonna bored to see because its like a basic icon
-yes like that, More concerned about pictures, if we take an icon or image from the internet, there is usually a maximum resolution of stomach pain around 42 * 42 pixels.
-if the handphone use S20 with high resolution, it will make the icon image broken
- the material icon is not a picture, they are a vector
-like that, if we open the vector, its actually not a picture its kind of formula or seomething
-so it didnt follow the handphone resolution
-like that, if there is a high resolution pixel, the icon wont broken
-so if we have a picture 42*42 pixel, and in my phone for example....
....with the low resolution, its clear but if we see it from a higher resolution the icon will be broken
-or it will be really small
-its fun and many to design on android, that's why I think starting from the material first, I think the basics for iOS aren't that different
-but i think the material was made up of why it is explained more deeply than iOS flat design.
-yes like that, i think thats my input for you guys
-Farhan: (so basically we must learn the material design first before design our android application right? because as you say just now playstore can rejected the apps)
-Yes, you right, but you dont have to always follow the material, material is not just a ..... what is it call?
-the material has a spacing-margin; the primary size must be considered the same as the font.
-so basically font, size, margin, padding, and colour, that was the primary one
-if we follow this 5 primary thing, even if we make a varied design it will be accepteddy google
-even if we make a weird design but we still followed that 5 thing, it could be accepted too
-usually , android have 3 color, named primary, secondary, and text(dark text, light text), moreover, now there is a dark mode, so there are more applications.
-so we have to make primaries light and primaries dark, secondary light and secondary dark the same dark text as light.
-As long as the color matches the points mentioned. Usually still accepted
So there is no need to really fixate on the material components
-Like that, as needed...
-Farhan:(so use it what are we need it right?)
-yes you right
-Farhan:(do you have other quesition akbar and hanif?)
-i think its enough
-Farhan: ( i just curious, do you make the website version too?)
-no , its not me, its other people
-is it bad ?
-Farhan :(no its actually not)