-Helo, Test
-Yes, Hello
-Yes, Oke
-Farhan : (Asking Permission for recording)
-Yes, you can
-Farhan : (Assalamu'alaikum)
-Wa'alaikumussalam
-Farhan : (Opening Discussion)
-Should we start now?
-its little bit delay
-now its fine, right?
-Yes, the important thing the sound is in
-This is just a discussion, bro. The point may be able to create feedback for us as well.
-Farhan : (Explaining about the discssuion and ask the developer should farhan tell the details of the assignment)
- Yes sure, How?
-Farhan : ( explain about the assignment)
-Hello? you explain until the design right?Sorry my internet changed
-Farhan : ( Continue to explain about the assignment)
-Yes, okay
-Okay, this won't take long. Just go straight ahead
-Is it Alright if i can't turn on my camera?
-Farhan: ( yes , its alright you can't)
-its dark in here
-has it appeared yet?
-OK, has it appeared yet?
-yes, its appeared
-Okay, from the first one, we just change the background
-As we can see, the original background was ferrari right?i think its slightly deviated from the goal
-Because there is no ferari car in this apps, so we put another car that suitable
-So jusrt like that from the first page
-then, for the register page is just the same
-But in the login page we added a feature "dont have an account", and this is linked to the register page
-So it's like making it easier for users. So you don't have to go back and forth to make a back, right?
-if we login, we entered the dashboard. and in the main menu i think we have to merge the history and reservation option
-yes the voice is in
-i think let akbar finish it first
-Farhan: (we are not changed the design entirely, we just change a couple think that probably need some improvement)
-Yes , just like terms of layout.
-I think we need to merge the reservation and history. Then i make history inside of the reservation menu then....
.....this button, history button. if we clicked it , we entered the history, like that
- So , the navigation bar isnt that full, one button can have many functions. so go to the about.
-Now in the "about" part, the information on the application information dashboard was moved here.
Well, here is a phone number, right here is an email, there is a web, then after that, there is a license, right?
-The application that you want the user believes. This application is reliable.
-Farhan : ( Just like the other application , there is a terms and policy right?)
-Farhan : ( for example, Liz transport doesnt responesible for the lost items)
-Then, there is a rate us button, i think this is an important button
-To make the application rate higher right? the last one is profile menu.
-Well, in the profile, right, in the original application, there is only an edit.
- so right now there is an already a change password and logout
-in the original app, the logout button was at top of the right in dashboard section right?
-if put it like that, im afraid user will confused about that button
-so i think it would be better if we put it on profile, so the user can be logout too.
-The save and edit still the same thing
-before, there isn't a change password right? i think this is an important button
-Because, if the user want to change the password, they can do it here
-Change password , anyother else, its a basic thing
-Then, after that, there is a logout button.
-Farhan : ( Talking about the logout button at the dashboard, i think not all people dont recognize that was a logout button)
-Farhan : ( so, i think it would be better if we put it in profile section ,just like other application)
-okay , the one on the dashboard isn't finished yet, Here, the main menu hasn't been discussed yet
-OK, let's go to the main menu. The first is for the driver. For example, before, when we click on the "menu," it immediately appears big cars, right?
-I think it takes up a lot of space, so it would be better if you make a column like this so it will be neatly arranged right
-Then after that, if we choose 1
-Farhan : ( we choose to make it grid, is because we inspired from other apps....
...like tokopedia, buka lapak and any other apps, that displayed greed when we search something)
-Then after that, we will choose 1...
-in the original apps, there is a description and an animation of a car.
-its just moving around, i think it would be better if we made it like a car image , preview and other else
-So i think it would be better if we make it like this, so the user now the detail of the car
-then, after that choos package
-this the inside of the choose package, if we click the request button, it will go directly to the with driver reservation
-Farhan: ( we can't reach the payment interface because we must do the transaction first, verify our identity and anyother else)
-Farhan: (Because of that , we cant improve the UI too)
-then after that, the rent car option. The rent car option is just same as the with driver option
- Yes, its just the same, the difference is only about the button name, if we click next the form is same too
-if we click the payment we go the rent a car reservation.
- the last one is the taxi menu, in this taxi menu , the changes in this taxi menu is quite a lot
-the first one is the address input, if we clicked the address, a satelite map will be appeared
-Farhan : ( its a hybrid map, the combination of satellite and roadmap type of map)
-there is a citizen house, i think its make the application heavy and wastefull
-Farhan :(As we know , in Indonesia there still so many people that using internet data package)
-Farhan : (i think it would be better if put a roadmap type in it )
-i think it would be better if it like this. its more slight and clear
-yes, its more clear to see
- we can see a tiny road in there
- Then , the original applciation, the choose button is right at the top of right corner
-as i see, its covering the header, so i think it would be better if we put it down here
-So it will be more user friendly
-then , after that, Oh yeah, for here, at first, the price per passenger was the form of input, right?
-When I changed the number of passengers, and it wasnt changed
- at the first its 120.000 then i change it to 200.000. after that i change the number of pasangger to 5
- its change to 120.000 again , it like the price is already fix but still can be change in the interface. i think its not effective...
-so i think it would be better if we make it label 120.000
-Farhan : (if it can be changed i think we can make it more cheaper, not a fix price)
- yes , its a fixed priced
- okay if we clicked the request, it will go directly to the taxi reservation
-okay i think thats all
-Farhan : (okay, thats all right?)
-yes thats all, the think left is the promo i think, can you tell it how it works?
-Farhan : (like this, if we click the promo, it will automated attached when we order something)
-Oh yes like that.
-Yes like that if we clicked the ok button